What are you prepared to do?
The Untouchables is a crime, history, thriller film directed by Brian De Palma.
Elliot Ness, an ambitious prohibition agent, is
determined to take down Al Capone.
In order to achieve this goal, he forms a group
given the nickname “The Untouchables”.
Eliot Ness, played by Kevin Costner.
Jim Malone, played by Sean Connery.
Al Capone, played by Robert De Niro.
Oscar Wallace, played by Charles Martin Smith.
George Stone, played by Andy Garcia.
Mike, played by Richard Bradford.
The Untouchables is a 1987 American crime film directed by Brian De
Palma, produced by Art Linson and written by David Mamet.
It stars Kevin Costner, Charles Martin Smith, Andy
García, Robert De Niro and Sean Connery.
Set in 1930 Chicago, the film follows Eliot Ness (Costner) as he forms the
Untouchables team to bring Al Capone (De Niro) to justice during Prohibition.
It is the third film on which De Niro and De Palma collaborated, after
Greetings (De Niro's first lead in a feature role) and Hi, Mom!.
The screenplay is loosely based on Ness's and Oscar Fraley's 1957 book The Untouchables and the
real-life events on which it is based, although most of its plot is fictionalized.
The Grammy Award-winning score is composed by Ennio Morricone
and features period music by Duke Ellington.
The Untouchables premiered on June 2, 1987, in New York City, and went
into general release on June 3, 1987, in the United States.
The film grossed $106.2 million worldwide and received
generally positive reviews from critics.
It was nominated for four Academy Awards; Connery won the Academy Award for Best Supporting
Actor, as well as the Golden Globe Award for Best Supporting Actor – Motion Picture.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, prohibition
era, gangster, baseball bat, white suit.
The tone is intense.